Sunil Manandhar

smanandhar@email.wm.edu | +1(757) 345-9788 | https://linkedin.com/in/sunil-manandhar | https://sunilmanandhar.com

RESEARCH

I am a Ph.D. candidate in the Department of Computer Science at William & Mary currently being advised by <u>Dr. Adwait Nadkarni</u>. My research focuses on the analysis and enforcement of security, safety, and privacy policies in modern operating systems. I am currently building and maintaining frameworks for smart home security and privacy policy analysis.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science, GPA 3.85 - The College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, VA

Aug 2016 - Present

Advisor: Dr. Adwait Nadkarni

Relevant Coursework: Advanced System Security Engineering, Advanced Topics in System and Security, CyberSecurity Research Analysis, Computer & Network Security, Advanced Software Engineering, Ubiquitous and Mobile Computing, Analysis of Algorithms, Intro to Machine Learning

BS in Computer Science and IT, GPA: 79.5% - Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu, Nepal

Nov 2011 - Nov 2015

PUBLICATIONS

Kaushal Kafle, Kevin Moran, **Sunil Manandhar**, Adwait Nadkarni, and Denys Poshyvanyk. Security in Centralized Data Store-based Home Automation Platforms: A Systematic Analysis of Nest and Hue. *ACM Transactions on Cyber Physical Systems, special issue on Security and Privacy for Connected CPS (TCPS)* [PDF]

Sunil Manandhar, Kevin Moran, Kaushal Kafle, Ruhao Tang, Denys Poshyvanyk, and Adwait Nadkarni. Towards a Natural Perspective of Smart Homes for Practical Security and Safety Analyses. *To Appear in the Proceedings of the 41st IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (S&P)*, San Francisco, CA, USA, May 2020. [PDF]

Kaushal Kafle, Kevin Moran, **Sunil Manandhar**, Adwait Nadkarni, and Denys Poshyvanyk. A Study of Data Store-based Home Automation. *In Proceedings of the 9th ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy (CODASPY)*, Dallas, TX, USA, March 2019. *Best Paper Award*. [Press Coverage] [PDF]

Sigmund Albert Gorski III, Ben Andow, Adwait Nadkarni, **Sunil Manandhar**, William Enck, Eric Bodden, and Alexandre Bartel. ACMiner: Extraction and Analysis of Authorization Checks in Android's Middleware. *In Proceedings of the 9th ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy (CODASPY)*, Dallas, TX, USA, March 2019. [CVE-2019-9351, CVE-2019-9377, CVE-2019-9438] [PDF]

WORK EXPERIENCE

COVES Fellow, Center for Innovative Technology

May 17 2021 -

Model statewide privacy policies for smart community Testbed

Co-op, IBMFramework for privacy policy analysis and compliance (ongoing)

- Created pipeline for NLP tasks
- □ Trained Named-Entity-Recognition (NER) Model
- □ Multi Label Classification using BERT

Research Intern, IBM

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

Framework for Privacy Policy analysis

Lead Grad Student, SPL Lab

Jan 2020 - Present

- Conducted weekly student-run meetings and organized events to improve research skills
- ☐ Managed lab website and logistics [Website]

_	Mentored 4 students in research projects	
Resea	rch Assistant, CS Department, William & Mary	May 2018 - Present
_	Analyzed Privacy Policies to develop insights into data protection practices (ongoing)	•
-	Designed framework for generating natural home automation scenarios to improve security and sa	afety in smart homes
۵	Developed proof of concept exploits for vulnerabilities in access control enforcement of APIs in the	he Android Platform
Teachi	ing Assistant, William & Mary	Aug 2016 - May 2017
_	Computational Problem Solving	
Techn	ology Lead, Universal Language Learning, China Built a chatbot engine for kids to help with language learning. https://my-little-harper.myshopify.co	Dec 2016 - Present
Mobil ⊐	e App Developer, Moondrop, San Francisco Managed Mobile Application and Updated the App with Material Design https://tinyurl.com/y65e	Jan 2016 - Aug 2016 eafd6
Softwa 	are Engineer, Bajra Technologies, Kathmandu, Nepal SiteHawk - Crawler, and Interface for WebsiteSite Deface Detection https://tinyurl.com/y4ro377 Imperial - Cordova based Mobile App for Side-Kick Plus Device https://tinyurl.com/y6dz3qjg	Jan 2015 - Jan 2016
	· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·	May 2014 - Dec 2014
<u> </u>	MyFarm - Mobile Application	
٦	Driving License Mobile App https://tinyurl.com/s6rjgmo	
	AWARDS AND HONORS	
<u> </u>	The Commonwealth of Virginia Engineering & Science (COVES) Fellow, 2021	
_ _	S. Laurie Sanderson Award for Excellence in Undergraduate Mentoring Award, 2021	
<u>-</u>	Distinguished Reviewer - Shadow PC, IEEE S&P 2021	
_	Best Paper Award at CODASPY, Dallas, TX, USA, March 2019	
_	Received 3 CVEs and mentions on the Android Security Bulletin	
_	Winner of Imagine Cup Nepal 2014	
_	Winner of Skype Challenge in Imagine Cup 2014	
_	President of Computer Science and Information Technology Association of Nepal (2014)	
_	Microsoft Student Partner - St. Xavier's College (2014)	
	PRESENTATIONS AND INVITED TALKS	
۵	"Towards a Natural Perspective of Smart Homes for Practical Security and Safety Analyses"	
	□ 41st IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy	
	□ IBM	
	Journal Club, William & Mary	
	"Outlier Detection in Large Scale Dataset"	
	□ 17th Annual Graduate Research Symposium	
	PROFESSIONAL SERVICE	
_	Shadow PC for IEEE S&P 2021	
	Sub-reviewer for Conferences	
	□ USENIX 2021	
	□ USENIX Safethings 2021	
	□ ISOC Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS), 2020	
	□ USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX), 2019	
	☐ The International Conference on Information Systems Security (ICISS), 2019	

Student Technology Advisory Committee (Arts and Science Department - William & Mary) (2020)	